<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="mygeneratedodd%20(Copy).rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="mygeneratedodd%20(Copy).rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt><title>TEI encoding for scholarly letters between Raymon Aron and his colleagues, Letter 2 by George H Nadel
            </title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Mathieu Taybi</authority>
                <availability> <p>restricted access</p></availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p> 
                    <idno>Archival reference : NAF 28060 (125) XV</idno> 
                    <origPlace>BNF Richelieu, Département des Manuscrits</origPlace>
                    <settlement>Paris</settlement>
                </p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <front>
            <head>
                <lang>English</lang>
                <title>
                    <affiliation>
                        History and Theory
                    </affiliation>
                    <persName>
                        Editor : George H Nadel, Executive Editor : Richard T Vann, Associate Editors : Louis O Mink, Richard
                        Buel, Assistant Editor : Jane K Parker,
                        Consultant Editor : W H Dray, Editorial Comitee : Raymond Aron, Isaiah Berlin, Fernand Braudel, E H Gombrich,
                        Sidney Hook, Maurice Mandelbaums, A D Momigliano, John Passmore, W H Waslh, C Vann Woodward
                        
                    </persName>
                </title>
                <address>
                    <addrLine>
                        Wesleyan Station, Middletown Connecticut 06457 USA
                    </addrLine>
                </address>
                <date>
                    26th October 1971
                </date>
            </head>
        </front>
        <body>
            <opener>
                <salute>Dear Professor Aron</salute>
            </opener>
            <div>
                <div>
                    <p>
                        <lb/>I am writing to you about tentative plans for assembling a small symposium to discuss <hi><term>Historicism</term></hi>
                        We are at the moment concerned mainly with subject matter. No decisions have yet been made about date, site, nnumers, or foundation
                        support. <date>Fall 1972</date> or <date>Spring 1973</date> are probable dates. I should greatly appreciate your help, answers,
                        and comments -- including negative comments.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <lb/>The overall objectives of the symposium would be any (or all) of the following: (1) To discuss the history of the impact
                        of <term>historicism</term> on some of the established disciplines. (2) To learn where <term>historicism</term> stands today
                        . (3) To attemps to reduce the variety of usages of the term <term>"historicism"</term> to some workable characterization and,
                        as a service to scholarshop, publicize our findings in <hi>History and Theory.</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <lb/>It would help in planning to determine what kind or kinds of <term>"historicism"</term> the symposium should usefully
                        confine itself. This need not be in contradiction to objective (3) ; it could be the first step towards it. For example,
                        Professor<persName>Mandelbaum</persName> -- at length in his recent <title>History, Man and Reason</title> and more briefly in his 
                        enclosed <title>Encyclopedia</title> article -- defines the term as the undestanding of phenomena through their place in a process 
                        of <hi>development.</hi> As a <hi>methodological principle</hi>, rather than a <term><foreign>Weltanschauung</foreign></term>
                        , he sees it to be relevant to such current topics of discussion as <persName>Piaget</persName>'s <term>developmentalism</term>, 
                        <term>structuralism</term> and as a reevaluation of <term>Marxism</term> (regarding <term>orthodox Marxism</term>as <term>historicist</term>
                        and <term>Marxian humanism</term>as <term>anti-historicist</term>). QUite differnt issues might be raised by other kinds of
                        characterizations, e.g. by <persName>Popper</persName>'s linking of <term>historicism</term> to <term>"holism"</term>(involving
                        i.a. the concepts of "laws") or by the identification of <term>historicism</term> with a concept of <term>"historicity"</term>of relevance to theology).
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <lb/><hi>Do you agree that our undertaking requires some prior narrowing down of the term, and if so, have you any wider-ranging
                        associations of <term>"historicism</term>in mind that might usefully be played down or excluded?</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <lb/>Participating speakers and auditors would mostrly represent specific disciplines.These might include "history" (perhaps a 
                        sruvey of the classic development of <term>historicism</term>), "historicim and art history", "historicim and philosophy", "historical
                        theology", "historicim and economics", as wells as, perhaps, "historicism and science" and the more recent "historicism and black history".
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <lb/><hi>Would you be willing, in principle, to attend? Could you also let me know on what topic you may
                        wish to read a paper (or shorter comment on some problem, book, or thinker)?</hi>
                    </p>               
                </div>
            </div> 
            <closer>
                <signed>Sincerly George H Nadel,
                    George H Nadel,
                    Warnham Lodge Horsham Susses England
                </signed>
            </closer>
            <postscript>
                <p></p>
            </postscript>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>    