<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="mygeneratedodd%20(Copy).rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="mygeneratedodd%20(Copy).rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt><title>TEI encoding for scholarly letters between Raymon Aron and his colleagues, Letter 3 by Richard T Vann
            </title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Mathieu Taybi</authority>
                <availability> <p>restricted access</p></availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p> 
                    <idno>Archival reference : NAF 28060 (125) XV</idno> 
                    <origPlace>BNF Richelieu, Département des Manuscrits</origPlace>
                    <settlement>Paris</settlement>
                </p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <front>
            <head>
                <lang>English</lang>
                <title>
                    <affiliation>
                        History and Theory
                    </affiliation>
                    <persName>
                        Editor : George H Nadel, Executive Editor : Richard T Vann, Associate Editors : Louis O Mink, Richard
                        Buel, Assistant Editor : Jane K Parker,
                        Consultant Editor : W H Dray, Editorial Comitee : Raymond Aron, Isaiah Berlin, Fernand Braudel, E H Gombrich,
                        Sidney Hook, Maurice Mandelbaums, A D Momigliano, John Passmore, W H Waslh, C Vann Woodward
                    </persName>
                </title>
                <address>
                    <addrLine>
                        Wesleyan Station, Middletown Connecticut 06457 USA
                    </addrLine>
                    <addrLine>
                        EHESS 54 boulevard Raspail 75270 Paris, Cedex 06 France
                    </addrLine>
                </address>
                <date>
                    October 20, 1978
                </date>
            </head>
        </front>
        <body>
            <opener>
                <salute>Dear Professor Aron</salute>
            </opener>
            <div>
                <div>
                    <p>
                        <lb/><hi>History and Theory</hi>, in collaboration with <placeName>Wesleyan's Center for the Humanities</placeName>
                        is planning a small conference for <date>next March</date>, to discuss issues raised in and by <persName>Hayden White</persName>
                        's book <title>Metahistory: The historical Imagination of Nineteenth century Europe.</title> Although one sees this book
                        increasingly cited in articles and other books, we believe that is has not received the thorough critical examination which it 
                        deserves. It is highly original in its application of <term>literary history</term>to the <term>history of historiography</term>
                        , and radical in its reformulation of <term>historical relativism</term> and other classic issues.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <lb/>The conference will be held in <placeName>Middletown</placeName>on <date>March 16th and 17th, 1979</date>
                        Main papare will be given by <persName>Maurice Mandelbaum</persName> (Philosophy, <placeName>John Hopkins and Dartmouth</placeName>
                        , <persName>Hans Kellner</persName>(History, <placeName>Michigan State</placeName>), <persName>Paul Hernadi</persName>(Comparative litterature
                        <placeName>Iowa</placeName>), and <persName>Edward Said</persName> (English, <placeName>Columbia</placeName>). There will be crtics
                        for each paper, and we plan to leave plenty of time for both formal and informal discussion. We plan to limit the conference to forty
                        participants, from history, literary theory and philosophy.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <lb/>We though that as a member of the Editorial Commitee you would like to know about the planning of this conference, and also
                        to know that of course you are invited if you are interested, in participating. Since the budget for the conference is very low we can't
                        offer to cover travel expanses, as we would like to do, but if you expect to be in the vicinity of <placeName>Middletown</placeName>
                        <date>next March</date> in any case, by all means do let us know. We shall also be happy to send copies of the main papers,  at your
                        request. Naturaly we hope that they will later be published in <hi>History and Theory</hi>
                    </p>       
                </div>
            </div> 
            <closer>
                <signed>Sincerely yours, Richard T Vann
                </signed>
            </closer>
            <postscript>
                <p></p>
            </postscript>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>    